Cuz they can take those for the next
hundred years. Yeah. Are you going to
put boots on the ground and then tell
Americans to expect ten thousand dead
soldiers in the next six months?
So now we're stuck.
And
>> [cough and clears throat]
>> there's also the video circulating
recent footage by the sun in the UK
showing the Iranian missiles emerging
from underground silos that are
completely like you can't tell it's the
desert. There's no even like there's
nothing to tell that below that there's
anything, you know, and um
>> [snorts]
>> The the the the announcement they made
yesterday from Iran that future launches
will carry warheads exceeding one ton.
Future attacks each war each missile
will be carrying warheads exceeding
one ton. I mean for twenty years the US
failed to defeat the the
the Taliban in Afghanistan when all they
were hiding in the mountains and in the
caves were AK-47s and RPG launchers and
you know, hidden weapon caches. So how
are they going to how are they going to
defeat this? We're not talking about
RPGs and AK-47s.
How how realistic I mean of course you
can bomb bomb an underground facility
just like they did with
Nasrallah but you need to know where it
is and they don't know where these ones
are.
No, they don't know. They don't know.
That's why they had to use a 30 ton bomb
last year when when bombing Iran.
Because they had an idea where it was,
they weren't sure if there was anything
in it and then Trump being Trump said
last year that the entire Iranian
nuclear program had been obliterated.
That was his word, obliterated. So
either he lied,
he was tricked,
or he's too stupid to know that he
wasn't able to obliterate it. Yeah,
because if
>> And now we're in a war. If it's been
obliterated then why are you stating now
that you're going to you you've you've
gone to this war because they were days
away from producing a nuclear weapon
which is something we've been hearing
for 30 days from Bibi Netanyahu.
>> You know, there's a video there's a
video going around.
Exactly. There's a video going around of
every time Netanyahu
said on the floor of the United States
Congress
that
that Iran is six months away from a
nuclear
Uh-huh.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
I think Americans Americans are now
coming to realization of this though.
We're aware of these lies. Yes.
You know, there's a kind of a mystery
going on right now too, Susie, as to
where exactly Netanyahu is. There were
reports that he was in Germany, he was
hiding in Germany. I heard today he's
hiding in Cyprus. Wherever he happens to
be, he's hiding.
You know, what kind of wartime leader is
that?
Yeah. Well, I mean they seem to to be on
the on his tracks a whole lot now. I
mean they seem to know
it's it's kind of like they're using his
playbook now, you know, I don't know how
they've managed. Maybe it's the Russians
feeding them like the satellite
reconnaissance and targeting
intelligence. I don't know if if it's
from the Russians or they've managed to
infiltrate with their agents like just
like they did
you know, the Israeli state but um they
did hit his house. They did target his
house and his brother was in in his
house and his brother is dead.
They [snorts]
are employing Israel's tactics of you
know, taking out taking out the heads
the leadership because they've also
targeted Ben Gvir's house and Ben Gvir I
don't know what is the latest but up
until
last night the reports was that he was
seriously injured.
Critically injured. So they're now
employing Israel's tactics.
They are. It's the same tactic.
Yes.
And and this has to this has to have
the Israelis on their on their heel.
You know, they
I don't think that they expected any of
this. No.
I think that the that the it was the
Israelis who convinced Trump that Iran
was a house of cards.
That the Israelis did that because they
actually believe themselves.
Well, they I mean they wanted to use the
they only have a
limited time left up until the midterm
elections and everyone all the analysts
saying even you that this is a last big
opportunity to take out Iran because
they're getting the feedback that the
American public has had it this time. So
time was running and they also have
their fall I think Israel there's also
fall elections in Israel. But um
Yes. Trump for for that matter Trump
came out yesterday. I mean you see him
with the press. He's making all these
like
crazy crazy ass statements. They're
asking him about the Tomahawks and he's
like I don't know, maybe I saw them
Tomahawks. I don't know. And then he was
making these he was throwing
um
Steve Witkoff
What's the name of his son-in-law? God,
Kushner. Jared Kushner. Yes and he said
under the bus saying, you know, they
gave me the info and that's why I
decided to you know, call call the war
and it was based on info that and he he
named them and he threw them under the
bus. So
I mean where does Jared Kushner come
into this anyway? He doesn't hold an
official position within the government.
So you're saying out publicly that
God, you're going by Jared Kushner's
suggestions that Iran is going to attack
us soon?
That's what you're telling the American
public? That's why you entered this war?
And let me let me add something to the
Russians made a statement today that
made perfect sense. The Russians said
that they will no longer engage in
settlement talks with the Ukrainians
that are that are headed by the United
States because the United States can't
be trusted. It was engaged supposedly in
talks with Iran pretending to go through
talks with Iran and then they attacked
Iran. So the Russians said why should we
trust the Americans to broker talks with
Ukraine when they could just as soon
turn around and attack us in the middle
of the talks.
And I think that's exactly right. Yeah,
I mean I mean
the two wars with Iran happened in the
middle of the so-called discussions that
America was having with Iran on on its
nuclear program. So I mean they can't be
trusted anymore and
Trump did reach out behind the scenes
twice in these ten days for a ceasefire
with the Iranians and they said they
played some games.
>> we've been told, yeah. Well, Bibi didn't
like it and he he was calling over at
the White House to see if these reports
were true, right? I mean what does this
what does this show? Who's running the
show? Who's who's the president of
America?
Or is the president of America president
of America or or is he representing
whose interests is he representing?
>> Honestly honestly on foreign policy
on foreign policy Benjamin Netanyahu has
just as much authority as whoever
happens to be president of the United
States.
We've conceded foreign policy to the
Israelis and to Israeli interests.
But John, it seems that they the
Americans are
inclined into asking for you know,
getting into
back channel talks for a ceasefire and
they're seeing it's not working and it
seems that Trump has called Putin and
asks asked for Putin's help on this.
Is this true? Have we heard anything?
>> I I I haven't heard that but I wouldn't
be surprised. So this was this was the
reporting coming in from Thanassis
Avgerinos. He's a very well respected
very well connected our Greek reporter
based in Moscow and this was his
reporting late last night on our big
Greek
channels.
That the report he has from the Kremlin
is that Donald Trump reached out to
Putin for him to intervene to hopefully
broker a ceasefire with Iran because
Iran isn't isn't
isn't having it. The the his two
attempts so far they they turned them
down.
So this is the report that's come out.
>> [snorts]
[sighs]
>> Yeah, I believe that and and I'll tell
you what, the the Russians have been
giving the Iranians targeting
information.
Um that was leaked a few days ago
and I remember reading it and and just
saying to a friend, well of course
they're giving the Iranians targeting
information. They're allies. We're
giving the Ukrainians targeting
information.
The the Russians gave the North
Vietnamese targeting information. We
gave the Afghan Mujahideen targeting
information and Stinger missiles. This
is what enemies do to one another.
So what's the best way to to get that to
stop? You just reach out directly to the
Russians and say please stop. Help us
negotiate some kind of a ceasefire. Oh,
let's see if it's true.
>> But but I'll I'll add one other thing,
Susie.
We here in the United States, we look
like fools.
We look like puppets of the Israelis and
we look like fools for being duped into
another yet another war of choice.
The 27 US military facilities across the
region have been struck even in Incirlik
airbase in Turkey which is one of the
key hubs for US air power for the whole
Middle East for decades has been hit and
rendered um unusable while several ports
that the US uses in the Gulf have also
been damaged. Even the the port that the
US was building in Oman because they
wanted to stop using the port in in
Dubai because of exposure and stuff.
Even that has been struck. So now the US
seems to be relying heavily on the ports
of in Europe and in India to ship
equipment over. So what does I want your
comment on this, please.
Yes, see this is yet another one of
those examples of that the United States
just never thought would happen and so
didn't prepare for. India is far from
the war zone. It's far, and it's hard to
get from India to the Persian Gulf.
Uh but this is
exactly what we should have expected.
The Iranians told us in advance that
this would quickly escalate into a
regional war. It did almost immediately,
and then the Iranians told us that they
would close the Strait of Hormuz.
They're in the process of of
closing the Strait of Hormuz. This
morning they attacked three ships, uh
two oil tankers and one cargo ship.
Like what
What did we think was going to happen?
They told us what was going to happen.
Yeah. And we just pretended not to hear.
So since you've touched upon that, the
economic cost of the war to America is
how much per day? I'm getting I'm I'm
I'm reading reports that it could be 800
million dollars a day, and then I'm
reading other reports that it could be
up to 2 billion dollars a day. So do you
have Yeah.
>> a clearer idea?
Yeah, Axios reported um
2 days ago, I think it was, that it was
between 2 and 3 billion dollars a day,
and it reminded me of a story not a
story, it reminded me of of an of an
incident where I was working I was
working at the CIA during the
uh Kuwait Iraq uh war, and it was right
before we began the liberation of
Kuwait. And I remember the president's
morning briefer coming back to the
office and saying that the president was
shocked to speechless
when they told him that we were spending
100 million dollars a day
in the Gulf. Well, 100 million back
then, yeah.
>> 100 million Well, just with inflation,
it's going to be close to 2 billion.
>> Yes.
And um there's there's
I mean there's all all these
repercussions, right? We're seeing um
something extraordinary happening